Michael D. Coe Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
Michael D. Coe Archives
1960-2014
ANTAR.000006
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
15
approximately; plus one map case
The archives of Michael D. Coe, accumulated during his time at Yale.
Coe, Michael D.
Biographical Sketch
Coe, Michael (b.1929) was Curator of Anthropology from 1968 to 1994. He is world famous for his research and publications on the Maya, the Olmec, and many other archaeological topics. His archaeological collections from the site of San Lorenzo Tenochtitlan are housed at the Peabody.
Education
- Ph.D. Harvard (1959)
Affiliations
- Central Intelligence Agency (1951-1954)
- University of Tennessee (1958-1960)
- Yale University (1960-present)
Description of the Material
Michael Coe's archives.
Mexico; Maps; Manuscript materials; Photographs; Field notebooks; Yale Peabody Museum; Yale University
- Maps, Series I
  - San Lorenzo Tenochtitlan area maps. Maps of the region around the San Lorenzo Tenochtitlan site used in research of the site., 000389
  - San Lorenzo Tenochtitlan. Set of four maps including San Lorenzo archaeology site map, soil series map, topographic map, and vegetation and land use. Also includes three page note by Dr. Coe about the maps., 000383
- Manuscript Materials, Series II
  - Atlas of Ancient America. 2 folders, one with notes, correpsondence etc. The other with manuscript., 034115
  - Fire God Paper., 034122
  - In the Land of the Olmec. Includes original figures and site maps related to San Lorenzo Tenochtitlan., 1980; 000397
  - Obsidian Trade at San Lorenzo Tenochtitlan, Mexico., 12 Nov 1971; 000406
  - The Maya. Revised Edition. Red binder with notes and outline., 034114
- Research Materials, Series III
  - Artifact Dating Techniques. Numerous papers, notes, etc. all having to do with dating techniques. Also includes copies of NFS proposals that propose work on said techniques as well as notes from a seminar given by Karl Turekian., 034113
  - Aztec Treasure., 034120
  - Glyph Research. Notes, photographs, drawings, etc., 034116
  - Maya Vases. 2 folders., 034121
  - Miscellaneous. Photocopies of plates., 034117
  - Spain Project. Never went forward., 034118
  - The Maya., 034119
- [Untitled], Series IV
  Scope and Contents
  San Lorenzo Research Material Series
  - San Lorenzo Tenochtitlan. Research Materials., 033971
  - San Lorenzo Tenochtitlan. Blue Binder #2, Box 2. Photographs of San Lorenzo Monuments., 033973
  - San Lorenzo Tenochtitlan. Box 6. 2 Red Binders, Vol. 1, 2: UT Press, original images., 034005
  - San Lorenzo Tenochtitlan. Photographs and labels used in Peabody Museum exhibit., 034086
- Guatemala, Series V
  Research Materials
  - Guatemala. Box 1. Pottery type and variety counts. Salinas la Blanca site. Also notes on modes and sherds discarded., 1962; 033952
  - Guatemala. Box 1.Guatemala Project correspondence, radiocarbon dates, Ecology of Ocos Region, Faunal and Floral remains, and Physical Analysis of pottery thin sections from Salinas la Blanca site., 1962; 033953
  - Guatemala. Box 1.Guatemala Project: Section profiles and notes on levels in the Salinas la Blanca sites. Patterns of settlement in the Ocos Region. Historical information on Popal Vuh., 1962; 033954
  - Guatemala. Box 1.Guatemala Project: Negatives, contact prints, photographs. La Victoria, Ocos Region. Images from Ecuador are for comparisons., 1962; 033955
  - Guatemala. Box 1.Field Catalogue1957., 1962; 033964
  - Guatemala. Box 1. Michael Coe. 1962. Diary., 033965
  - Guatemala. Box 1. La Victoria Notes., 033966
  - Guatemala. Box 1. Denton Correspondence., 033967
  - Guatemala. Box 1. Salinas La Blanca: Original note cards of pottery type descriptions., 033970
  - Guatemala. Box 5. Pacific Coast Guatemala., 034003
  - Guatemala. Box 5. Lago Isabal, Guatemala.. 27 aerial photgraphs., 034004
- Costa Rica, 1959-1960; Series VI
  - Costa Rica. Box 1.Costa Rica Field notes., 1959-1960; 033957
  - Costa Rica. Box 1. Project Expenses., 1959-1960; 033962
  - Costa Rica. Box 1.Mike Coe, Site Book 1960., 033958
  - Costa Rica. Box 1. Costa Rica, Field diaries., 033959
  - Costa Rica. Box 1. Catalog #2., 033960
  - Costa Rica. Box 1. Catalog #1., 033961
  - Costa Rica. Box 1. Negatives and Photographs., 033963
  - Costa Rica. Box 1. Correspondence: Business, etc., 033968
  - Costa Rica. Box 1. Correspondence: Guanacaste Province., 033969
  - Costa Rica. Aerial Photographs. 2 boxes., 034083
  - Costa Rica. Faunal data. 2 folders., 034087
  - Costa Rica. Sherd Counts., 034088
  - Costa Rica. Field drawings., 034089
  - Costa Rica. Pottery Paste analysis information., 034090
  - Costa Rica. Reports; Publications., 034091
  - Costa Rica. Radiocarbon Dating., 034092
  - Costa Rica. Ceramic Analysis codes., 034093
  - Costa Rica. Ceramic Analysis., 034094
  - Costa Rica. Illustrations. (Sweeney dissertation?)., 034095
  - Costa Rica. Photocopied Illustrations from Sweeney dissertation., 034096
  - Coe archives. Jeanne Sweeney Dissertation 1975 Guanacaste Costa Rica: An Analysis of Precolumbian Ceramics From The Northwest Coast., 036082
- Field Notes, Series VII
  - Rio Chiquito Project., 034025
  - San Lorenzo Tenchtitlan. Includes site maps, excavation drawings., 1966-1968; 000400
- Correspondence, Series VIII
  - Correspondence. Box 6. Rio Chiquito Project General. 3 folders., 034016
  - Correspondence. Box 6. Rio Chiquito Project Field Correspondence. 2 folders., 034017
  - Correspondence. Box 6. Rio Chiquito Project: Artist Correspondence., 034018
  - Correspondence. Box 6. Rio Chiquito Project: Ethnology Correspondence., 034019
  - Correspondence. Box 6. Rio Chiquito Project: Radiocarbon, etc. Correspondence., 034020
  - Correspondence. Box 6. Rio Chiquito Project: Yale Correspondence., 034021
  - Correspondence. Box 6. Rio Chiquito Project: Ecology, etc. Correspondence., 034022
  - Correspondence. Box 6. Rio Chiquito Project: Photogrammetry Correspondence., 034023
  - Correspondence. Box 6. Rio Chiquito Project: Personnel Correspondence., 034024
  - Inter-Departmental Correspondence. Box 6, 1 folder. general corespondence (to be filed separate from field documentation)., 034012
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence., 035880
- Collaborators, Series IX
  - Robert H. Cobean. Miscellaneous notes on obsidian research., 034106
  - Zeitlin. Miscellaneous, obsidian research. Realted to Cobean., 034107
- Miscellaneous, Series X
  - 1492. 6 folders: Notes, catalogs, essays, photographs, correspondence on objects to display in exhibit Circa 1492, in reference to the 500th anniversary of Columbus exhibit curated by Mike Coe and Ben Rouse at the National Gallery Smithsonian in 1992., 034110
  - Mount Lebanon Shaker Village. Folders of photos related to the Circa 1492 exhibit curated by Coe and Rouse at the National Gallery in 1992., 034111
  - Photographs, Drawings, Slides, Negatives. Miscellaneous photographs, slides and negatives and drawings of sites, artifacts etc., 035879
  - Slides. Miscellaneous slides from various locations, possibly used for teaching., 035195
- Oral Histories, Series XI
  - 4.23.2013. Oral History with Michael D. Coe conducted by Samantha Murphy and Maureen White on 4.23.2013. (2 tapes)., 034378
  - 5.10.2013. Oral History with Michael D. Coe conducted by Samantha Murphy and Maureen White on 5.10.2013., 034379
  - 6.5.2013. Oral History with Michael D. Coe conducted by Samantha Murphy and Maureen White on 6.5.2013., 034380
  - 9.18.2013. Oral History with Michael D. Coe conducted by Samantha Murphy and Maureen White on 9.18.2013., 034381
- Mount Lebanon Shaker Village, Series XII
  - Mount Lebanon Shaker Village. Photographs and card catalog. Artifacts collected., 034098
  - Mount Lebanon Shaker Village. Artifact catalog from North Family Mill Site. Appendix 9 of report. 2 lists., 034099
  - Mount Lebanon Shaker Village. Artifact catalog from North Family Brethren's Workshop., 034100
  - Mount Lebanon Shaker Village. Artifact catalog from North Family dump site., 034101
  - Mount Lebanon Shaker Village. Floor plan drawings of the North Family Brethren Family Workshop., 034102
  - Mount Lebanon Shaker Village. 35mm slides. 1 slide box. scanned., 034103
  - Mount Lebanon Shaker Village. Newspaper clipping. "Last Four Shakers Endure" 2006 LA Times., 034104
  - Mount Lebanon Shaker Village. Miscellaneous Shaker Village. 8 folders. Photographs, catalogues, notes, etc. document box and flat box., 034108